The world saw evil that day. Two men saw something else.
World Trade Center is a drama, history, thriller film directed by Oliver Stone.
Two police officers struggle to survive when they become trapped beneath
the rubble of the World Trade Center on September 11, 2001.
John McLoughlin, played by Nicolas Cage.
Donna McLoughlin, played by Maria Bello.
Steven McLoughlin, played by Connor Paolo.
JJ McLoughlin, played by Anthony Piccininni.
Erin McLoughlin, played by Alexa Gerasimovich.
Caitlin McLoughlin, played by Morgan Flynn.
World Trade Center is a 2006 American docudrama disaster film
directed by Oliver Stone and written by Andrea Berloff.
Starring Nicolas Cage and Michael Peña, the film is based on the experience of a team of Port Authority Police Officers during
the September 11 attacks, in which they were trapped inside the rubble of the collapsed World Trade Center.
The film was shot between October 2005 and February 2006, and theatrically
released in the United States by Paramount Pictures on August 9, 2006.
It was met with generally positive reviews from
critics and grossed $163 million worldwide.
The film explores themes of rescue, hero, alarm clock, war on terror, runaway.
The tone is emotional and intense.